Thomas Nelson

Henderson, NV 89011

Phone: (925) 639-2458 | **Email**: thnlsn.dev@gmail.com | **Portfolio**: https://www.thnlsn.me **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/thnlsn | **GitHub**: https://github.com/thnlsn

Summary

Self-driven front end web developer on and off the clock. I have a passion for problem-solving and creativity, especially in JavaScript, not just by creating user-friendly and responsive experiences on the front end with frameworks and preprocessors like React and Sass, but with servers, database structures, and APIs on the back end. My teamwork and leadership experience from my State Department internship in the Philippines lends itself nicely to the collaborative nature of this field and my work as front end developer at Neoboard has given me professional experience in an agile workflow, as well as in communication to both technical and non-technical personnel. I believe these traits and my natural hunger to learn are invaluable to the world of software and web development.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, React, Sass, HTML, CSS, Sass, jQuery, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, Node, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, Google Maps API, Git, GitHub, Node, NPM, Figma, Restful APIs, Agile, Sprint, Atlassian

Projects

Mind Garden | https://github.com/thnlsn/mind-garden
A daily planner that aims to streamline your day while also helping you practice daily gratitude.
All data is stored on your local machine as privacy and ease of use was of utmost importance.

- Tools: React, Sass, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, localStorage, Responsive Design **Electoral Map** | https://thnlsn.github.io/electoral-map/ | https://thnlsn.github.io/electoral-map/ Calculate and visualize a mock presidential election with an interactive map of U.S. electoral college.
 - Tools: React, Sass, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Responsive Design

World Clock | https://github.com/thnlsn/world-clock A live-updating analog clock (built with pure CSS) of your local timezone. Click on other zones to see it update and reflect their local times accordingly.

• Tools: React, Sass, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Responsive Design

Experience

Front-End Web Developer at Neoboard - Riverside, CA (Feb 2020 - Present):

- Building and maintaining a modern and responsive React-based front end for both the main website and messaging application, the latter of which I am wholly responsible over.
- Working closely with the back end engineers to integrate our custom built Restful API.
- Responsible for adding features directly requested by future clients.

Full-Stack Web Developer at Hack for LA - Los Angeles, CA (Feb 2020 - Present):

• Working with teams to build real-world projects that solve civic issues in the city of Los Angeles, often specifically requested by and partnered with companies and organizations in the area.

U.S. Department of State Intern - Manila, Philippines (June 2017 - Sept 2017):

- Constructed a new paperless workflow for procurement actions in the contracting section.
- Took initiative to create online surveys and film/edit videos of residences for the housing section.
- Guided incoming Foreign Service Officers and their families during check-in processes.
- Designed more practical spreadsheets and databases for the General Services Office.

Education

Bootcamp Certificate: University of California, Riverside (Issued Jan 2020): A 24-week intensive program for Full Stack Development, focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handelbars.js & React.

Bachelor of Arts, Political Science: University of California, Riverside (Sept 2015 - June 2019)